BU Records: Alpha Lambda Delta, Inclusive: 1955-1973, undated. Bulk: 1960-1969
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Alpha Lambda Delta
Inclusive: 1955-1973, undated. Bulk: 1960-1969
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/189
Alpha Lambda Delta. Baylor University Chapter.
1 document box
BU Records: Alpha Lambda Delta contains chapter materials from 1955-1973, which includes literary productions, correspondence, and financial documents related to the chapter's activity from those years.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
The Alpha Lambda Delta National Honor Society was originally founded as an honor society for freshmen women in 1924 at the University of Illinois by Maria Leonard, Dean of Women. The organization then spread to become a national organization when a chapter was charted at Purdue University in 1926. Its first national convention was held at the University of Illinois in 1930. In 1938, it was decided that the organization would begin to offer scholarships to promising graduate students. Alpha Lambda Delta remained as a single sex organization until 1976 where it became co-educational in response to changes made by Title IX. The Baylor chapter was founded on 29 April 1958 and continues to operate to this day.
Scope and Content
BU Records: Alpha Lambda Delta consists of materials from 1955-1973, with some undated materials. The materials reflect the activities of the chapter during the selected years. At the time, the organization was a women's only organization.
Series I: Chapter Files contains the correspondence, literary productions, chapter and member information, and correspondence of the organization.
Arrangement
Prior to processing, this collection was organized in three binders with tags arranged by subject. The binders also contained materials from a similar date range. For this current round of processing, the materials were kept in their original order.
Currently, this collection has one series, I. Chapter Files.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/189. Acquired 1982-08-31
Related Resources
Related references
“Our History.” Alpha Lambda Delta. Accessed October 14, 2019.
“Texas Chapters.” Alpha Lambda Delta. Accessed October 14, 2019.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Alpha Lambda Delta. Baylor University Chapter.; Alpha Lambda Delta.; Baylor University -- Societies, etc.
Subjects
College students -- Texas -- Waco -- Societies, etc.; Financial records.; Handbooks and manuals.; Records (Documents); Women -- Societies and clubs -- Texas -- Waco.
Genres
Correspondence.
- Chapter Files, 1955-1973, undated.; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondence, chapter files, literary productions and the financial documents of the Baylor chapter. The series is in good condition.
  - Binder I: National Officers, Chapter Role, 1955-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Binder I: Order Blanks, Local Membership, Awards, Constitution, History, 1957-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Binder I: Chapter Report, Financial Reports, Handbook, Ritual, 1957-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Binder II: Chapter Roll, Local Membership, Awards, Constitution, Order Blanks, 1961-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Binder II: National Officers, Annual Reports, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Binder II: Handbook, Ritual, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Binder III: National Offices, Chapter Roll, Map, Local Membership, 1968-1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Binder III: Awards, Constitution, History, Order Blanks, Annual Reports, 1967-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Binder III: Handbook, Current Correspondence, Ritual, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)